<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Instant News Portal</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.isis.poly.edu/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 17:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to join a node in a docker swarm</title>
		<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu/how-to-join-a-node-in-a-docker-swarm/</link>
					<comments>http://www.isis.poly.edu/how-to-join-a-node-in-a-docker-swarm/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 17:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.isis.poly.edu/?p=37</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jack Wallen walks through the steps to join new nodes to a Docker swarm as a worker and manager to help manage larger Docker clusters. Do you have a docker swarm up and running and need to add more nodes to it? You probably remember how getting started with Docker Swarm introduced you to the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>
<p>    Jack Wallen walks through the steps to join new nodes to a Docker swarm as a worker and manager to help manage larger Docker clusters.  Do you have a docker swarm up and running and need to add more nodes to it?  You probably remember how getting started with Docker Swarm introduced you to the join command.  The join token from that command can only be used once, so even if you copy that command to a file, it won&#8217;t work for a new node.  Fortunately, however, Docker developers have made it possible to add new nodes to a swarm at any time.  To do this, you need to have a Docker swarm up and running with at least one controller node and a new node to join.  You can add as many nodes as you need and can do so at any time.  You can join a node as a worker or manager.  The difference is simple: manager nodes elect a leader to manage orchestration tasks, whereas worker nodes receive and execute tasks sent from manager nodes.  Presumably, you&#8217;ll join the node as a worker, but I&#8217;ll show you the commands for both.  First, let&#8217;s join a node as a worker.  Log in to your Docker Swarm controller node and issue the docker swarm join-token worker command.  The output will include the docker swarm join command that you run on the new worker node.  If you want to create a new token, use the rotate option like this: docker swarm join-token &#8211;rotate worker.  Now, if you want to join a node as a manager, the command is docker swarm join-token manager.  To create a new join token, you can use the rotate option in the same way as with the docker swarm join-token &#8211;rotate manager.  Once you run one of those commands on your new node, it will join the swarm as a worker or a manager, and you&#8217;re ready to develop and manage a larger Docker cluster.  Subscribe to TechRepublic&#8217;s How To Make Tech Work on YouTube for Jack Wallen&#8217;s latest technology advice for business professionals.<br />
<br /><a href="https://www.techrepublic.com/article/how-to-join-node-docker-swarm/">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.isis.poly.edu/how-to-join-a-node-in-a-docker-swarm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brain implants allow paralyzed people to walk using their thoughts</title>
		<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu/brain-implants-allow-paralyzed-people-to-walk-using-their-thoughts/</link>
					<comments>http://www.isis.poly.edu/brain-implants-allow-paralyzed-people-to-walk-using-their-thoughts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 02:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.isis.poly.edu/?p=34</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gert-Jan Oskam was living in China in 2011 when he was in a motorcycle accident that left him paralyzed from the hips down. Now, with a combination of devices, scientists have given him back control over his lower body. &#8220;For 12 years I&#8217;ve been trying to get my legs back,&#8221; Mr Oskam said at a]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gert-Jan Oskam was living in China in 2011 when he was in a motorcycle accident that left him paralyzed from the hips down.  Now, with a combination of devices, scientists have given him back control over his lower body.  &#8220;For 12 years I&#8217;ve been trying to get my legs back,&#8221; Mr Oskam said at a press briefing on Tuesday.  &#8220;Now I&#8217;ve learned how to walk naturally, naturally.&#8221;  In a study published Wednesday in the journal Nature, researchers in Switzerland described implants that provided a &#8220;digital bridge&#8221; between Mr. Oskam&#8217;s brain and his spinal cord, bypassing the injured parts.  The invention allows Mr Oskam, 40, to stand, walk and climb a steep ramp with only the aid of a walker.  More than a year after the implant was inserted, he retained these abilities and actually showed signs of neurological recovery, walking with crutches even after the implant was removed.  Grégoire Courtaine, a spinal cord specialist at the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology, Lausanne, who led the study, said at a press briefing.  Neuroscientist Jocelyn Bloch.  &#8220;It was quite science fiction for me at the beginning, but today it has become reality,&#8221; added Mr Oskam, who implanted Mr Oskam at the University of Lausanne.  In recent years there have been several advances in technological spinal cord injury treatment.  In 2016, a group of scientists led by Dr. Courtin managed to restore the ability to walk in paralyzed monkeys and helped another man regain control of his paralyzed arm.  In 2018, a different team of scientists, led by Dr Courtin, developed a way to stimulate the brain with electrical-pulse generators, allowing partially paralyzed people to walk and cycle again.  Last year, more advanced brain stimulation methods allowed paralyzed people to swim, walk and cycle within a day of treatment.  Mr.  Oskam underwent stimulation procedures in earlier years, and even regained the ability to walk, but eventually his progress plateaued.  At the press briefing, Mr. Oskam said that these stimulation technologies made him feel that there was something alien about locomotion, an alien distance between his mind and body.  The new interface changed that, he said: “Earlier the stimulus was controlling.  I am, and now I am controlling the impulse.”  In the new study, the brain-spinal interface, as the researchers call it, took advantage of an artificial intelligence thought decoder to read Mr. Oskam&#8217;s intentions — detectable as his electrical signals.  brain &#8211; and their muscle movements to match.  The etiology of natural movement, from thought to intention, was preserved.  The only addition, as Dr.  Courtaine describes the digital bridge spanning the injured parts of the spine.  Andrew Jackson, a neuroscientist at Newcastle University who was not involved in the research, said: &#8220;It raises interesting questions about autonomy, and the source of order. You keep blurring the philosophical boundaries between what the brain is and what technology is.&#8221;  Dr. Jackson added that scientists in the field have theorized about connecting the brain to spinal cord stimuli for decades, but this represents the first time they&#8217;ve achieved such success in a human patient. &#8220;It&#8217;s easy to say, it&#8217;s much harder to do.&#8221; ,&#8221; he said. To achieve these results, the researchers first implanted electrodes on Mr. Oskam&#8217;s skull and spine. The team then used a machine-learning program to observe which parts of the brain lit up as he tried to move different parts of his body. This thought decoder is specific. were able to match the activity of specific electrodes to the target: one configuration lit up whenever Mr. Oskam tried to move his ankle, another when he tried to move his hip. The researchers then used another algorithm to connect the brain implant to the spinal implant, which was in his body. Different parts were set to send electrical signals, sparking movement. The algorithm was able to account for slight changes in the direction and speed of each muscle contraction and relaxation.  And, because the signals between the brain and spinal cord were sent every 300 milliseconds, Mr. Oskam could quickly adjust his technique based on what was working and what wasn&#8217;t.  He can twist his hip muscles within the first treatment session  Over the next few months, researchers fine-tuned the brain-spinal interface to better accommodate basic actions like walking and standing.  Mr. Oskam regained a somewhat healthy range of motion and was able to navigate steps and ramps with relative ease without treatment for several months.  Furthermore, after a year of treatment, he began to notice a clear improvement in his movement without the aid of a brain-spinal interface.  Researchers documented these improvements in weight bearing, balance and walking tests  Now, Mr Oskam can walk limited distances around his home, get in and out of cars and stop at a bar for a drink.  For the first time, she said, she felt like she was in control  The researchers acknowledge the limitations of their work  It is difficult to distinguish subtle motives in the brain, and although the current brain-spine interface is suitable for walking, the same probably cannot be said for restoring upper body movement.  Treatment is also invasive, requiring multiple surgeries and hours of physical therapy.  The current system does not correct all spinal cord paralysis  But the team is hopeful that further advances will make the treatment more accessible and more systemically effective  &#8220;That&#8217;s our real objective,&#8221; said Dr. Courtaine, &#8220;to make this technology available around the world to all patients who need it.&#8221;<br />
<br /><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/05/24/science/paralysis-brain-implants-ai.html">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.isis.poly.edu/brain-implants-allow-paralyzed-people-to-walk-using-their-thoughts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Explaining Blockchain Capital&#8217;s Big Bet on Eyeball-Scanning Rooms</title>
		<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu/explaining-blockchain-capitals-big-bet-on-eyeball-scanning-rooms/</link>
					<comments>http://www.isis.poly.edu/explaining-blockchain-capitals-big-bet-on-eyeball-scanning-rooms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 01:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.isis.poly.edu/?p=31</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, WorldCoin, an outfit that aims to serve as proof of personality in a world where it&#8217;s increasingly difficult to distinguish a human from a bot, raised $115 million in Series C funding. Led by 10-year-old venture firm Blockchain Capital, whose bets include Coinbase, Kraken and OpenC, the investment brings WorldCoin&#8217;s funding to at]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
				This week, WorldCoin, an outfit that aims to serve as proof of personality in a world where it&#8217;s increasingly difficult to distinguish a human from a bot, raised $115 million in Series C funding.  Led by 10-year-old venture firm Blockchain Capital, whose bets include Coinbase, Kraken and OpenC, the investment brings WorldCoin&#8217;s funding to at least $240 million, even as the controversial company — founded in 2019 by OpenAI CEO Sam Altman — has a lot to prove.  Yesterday, we spoke with Blockchain Capital General Partner Spencer Bogart about what gave him confidence in WorldCoin, which aims to create a global ID, a global currency and an app that enables payments, purchases and transfers.  Like many others, we wondered how it could achieve its goals when, at least for now, its mission rests first and foremost on convincing billions of people to allow WorldCoin to scan their irises using a futuristic, technology-dense globe.  Below is part of that conversation, edited for length.  You can also listen to longer conversations here.  Your co-investors in this new round include previous backers Andreessen Horowitz, Bain Capital Crypto and Distributed Global.  Have Khosla Ventures or Tiger Global, the previous backers, re-engaged?  They can be part of this financing;  I don&#8217;t believe they are a big part of it.  How many companies do investors own?  I guess it&#8217;s difficult to negotiate with Sam Altman because of the power he has and his extensive experience on the other side of the table as an investor.  This is an accurate characterization.  Sam is a strong founder and knows how to run a cap table.  Again, I apologize.  It is not a statistic in front of me right now.  Generally, companies sell 20% [equity] In every financing.  Well, things can go significantly down or up from there.  I think in this case, the number is going to be meaningfully lower than Series A, Series B and Series C.  How long have you been talking to WorldCoin and what inspired you to lead this deal?  Sam wondered if the real genesis was: What if I could create a cryptocurrency that I could distribute to everyone in the world and everyone gets an equal share of it?  For me, from an entrepreneurial perspective, it&#8217;s definitely interesting [though] I don&#8217;t know that it&#8217;s something that we would be very excited to go and underwrite based on the things that our team is generally interested in.<br />
[Meanwhile] This essentially requires ensuring that no one person accumulates a disproportionate share of it, which requires people to be able to identify unique people.  And this really gets into the part that we&#8217;re excited about, which is the world ID.  It is this ability to easily distinguish between machines and humans on the Internet [because] Most of the Internet is supported by advertising revenue and it costs just as much to serve bot traffic as it does to serve human traffic.  This is why various applications and service providers have used captcha to differentiate between bots and humans.  But in the world of advanced automated systems and especially things powered by AI, this is no longer the case.  It doesn&#8217;t even distinguish between unique humans, so I don&#8217;t know if the same person is coming to receive an additional asset, which leads us to: OK, how can we provide a way to distinguish between humans and bots and ensure that every human Unique?  Which leads to biometrics.  Biometrics are at the core of what defines humans, and my first thought was: Why build this custom hardware to scan the eyeball?  As such, billions of people are already walking around with an iPhone.  Why don&#8217;t we use Face ID, right?  The problem is that human facial structures do not have enough randomness, or entropy, to differentiate between unique people, at the scale of tens of thousands or hundreds of thousands of people.  I didn&#8217;t realize that was the case.  This is not something that has happened to me either.  I didn&#8217;t think about the fact that once you get past a hundred million people, there&#8217;s going to be a lot of people who look like Spencer Bogart;  Their facial structure is not sufficiently distinguishable from mine.  Fingerprints have the same problem;  Fingerprints do not have enough randomness.  This leads us to two viable options, DNA that has enough randomness to be able to prove human uniqueness on the scale of billions of people.  But you are providing too much information with DNA.  Then there are irises.  It turns out that the human iris has an insane amount of entropy and randomness.  And in this case, the team has built an insane amount of protection.  You get an iris scan, it doesn&#8217;t save your iris by default.  It is immediately deleted on the device.  It is only used to generate an iris code, which is a unique mapping or encoding of your iris.  And it is compared with all others.  And now, with these iris codes, we don&#8217;t know their names or locations or anything.  All we know about them all is that they are unique people.  I guess an enterprise strategy — helping companies minimize their interactions with bots — is the most lucrative opportunity for WorldCoin right now.  You can also deliver this cryptocurrency to everyone, although it&#8217;s not clear to me how people will use it.  But before any of that can happen, you need to get a meaningful number of people in front of these orbs that are weird and not easily accessible, when people are already worried about biometrics and cryptocurrency.  WorldCoin says it has now scanned 2 million people&#8217;s eyes.  How many are needed for this to be meaningful?  Ten million?  This is the right question.  About it: Do you have a network of proven unique people?  And it&#8217;s only going to be interesting for applications and enterprises at a certain scale.  But I think it will depend on the use case.  By the time you get to 10 million unique users, there are already a lot of applications that want to use it, others won&#8217;t be interested in using it unless you&#8217;re on a network of 500 million or a billion or 2.  Billions of people.  Some of the other challenges here are yes, obviously, room distribution.  Currently there are 200 to 300 [orbs] In the wild today, with more than 2,000 that have been produced and are waiting to be deployed.  Then there is this question of public perception.  Something we flagged as part of the investment is: Is there going to be such a negative perception of it that no matter how confident we are that it&#8217;s 100% sustainable, is the public perception going to be so negative that people won&#8217;t want to participate?  So far, the data says otherwise.  WorldCoin has already onboarded nearly 2 million people by operating a pretty capital-intensive boots-on-the-ground strategy, and it&#8217;s only in beta testing.  This is without pushing or pulling any levers of marketing;  This protocol is even without mainnet live.  This is only in preliminary testing.  As for some of the things it could be used for, Elon Musk talked a lot about a bot problem on Twitter, and if we could pay everyone $8 a month, it would help solve the bot problem.  We think that World ID is a low-friction way of solving the same problem and will be a high-fidelity solution.  And there are many new applications and services that historically did not exist because of our inability to make this distinction  What they are, I don&#8217;t know, but we are interested in financing them.  Again, you can hear more about the investment here, including why OpenAI itself could one day become a major customer of Worldcoin, why Bogart wasn&#8217;t bothered when hackers recently installed password-stealing malware on the devices of multiple Worldcoin orb operators, and why he flash trades on the blockchain. Fascinated by<br />
<br /><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2023/05/26/explaining-blockchain-capitals-big-bet-on-an-eyeball-scanning-orb/">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.isis.poly.edu/explaining-blockchain-capitals-big-bet-on-eyeball-scanning-rooms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New research confirms: 20% of adults do not want children</title>
		<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu/new-research-confirms-20-of-adults-do-not-want-children/</link>
					<comments>http://www.isis.poly.edu/new-research-confirms-20-of-adults-do-not-want-children/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.isis.poly.edu/?p=21</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The term &#8220;childfree&#8221; is used to describe individuals or couples who have made a conscious decision not to have children. This choice is often influenced by a variety of factors, including personal preference, lifestyle considerations, financial considerations, career aspirations, or concerns about overpopulation or environmental impact. Last summer, researchers at Michigan State University announced that]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The term &#8220;childfree&#8221; is used to describe individuals or couples who have made a conscious decision not to have children.  This choice is often influenced by a variety of factors, including personal preference, lifestyle considerations, financial considerations, career aspirations, or concerns about overpopulation or environmental impact.  Last summer, researchers at Michigan State University announced that about 1.7 million adults in Michigan, about one in five, have chosen not to have children, thus living a child-free life.  This figure was remarkably large, surprising many, and was later confirmed by a study  &#8220;We found that 20.9% of Michigan adults do not want children, which closely matches our previous estimate of 21.6%, and that means more than 1.6 million Michiganders are child-free,&#8221; said Jennifer Watling Neal, MSU professor of psychology and co-author of the study. .  &#8220;Michigan is similar to the U.S. as a whole in terms of population, so that could mean 50 million to 60 million Americans are child-free.&#8221;  The new study, published in PLOS ONE, attempted to replicate the original study using the same method, but with a new sample of humans.  The researchers used data from a representative sample of 1,000 adults who completed MSU&#8217;s State of the State survey, administered by the university&#8217;s Institute for Public Policy and Social Research.  To avoid any risk of cherry-picking results, the researchers pre-registered the study by recording in advance how the study would be conducted and what they hoped to find.  age, education or income,” said Zachary Neal, associate professor of psychology at MSU and co-author of the study.  &#8220;However, child-freedom is slightly more common among adults who are male, white or who have always been single.&#8221;  Some worry that child-free adults will regret their decision not to have children, especially later in life.  But Watling Neil explained &#8220;We found no evidence that older child-free adults experienced more life regrets than older parents. In fact, older parents were slightly more likely to want to change something about their lives.&#8221;  &#8220;Because many people are child-free, researchers say this group gets more attention, especially since reproductive rights are being eroded. Reproductive health care can force many people to have children even if they don&#8217;t want to, which is very concerning,&#8221; Neal said. The research team is now examining how abortion restrictions influence adults&#8217; choices to be childfree and is expanding their work beyond Michigan to include other states and countries. Reference: &#8220;Prevalence, Age of Decision, and Interpersonal Warmth Judgments of Childfree Adults: Replication and Extension&#8221; Jennifer Watling Neal and Zachary P. Neal, 5 Apr. 2023, PLOS ONE.DOI: 10.1317 /journal.pone.0283301<br />
<br /><a href="https://scitechdaily.com/new-study-confirms-20-of-adults-dont-want-children/">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.isis.poly.edu/new-research-confirms-20-of-adults-do-not-want-children/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>All screen time matters for eye health &#8211; CNET</title>
		<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu/all-screen-time-matters-for-eye-health-cnet/</link>
					<comments>http://www.isis.poly.edu/all-screen-time-matters-for-eye-health-cnet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 18:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.isis.poly.edu/?p=15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anyone who&#8217;s lost track of three hours staring at their computer may be familiar with the feeling of eyeballs plastered to the screen. As it turns out, staring at our phones, tablets and laptops for many hours a day is not good for our eyes. This can cause symptoms of digital eye strain, which stems]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anyone who&#8217;s lost track of three hours staring at their computer may be familiar with the feeling of eyeballs plastered to the screen.  As it turns out, staring at our phones, tablets and laptops for many hours a day is not good for our eyes.  This can cause symptoms of digital eye strain, which stems from the hard work our eyes have to do when navigating a screen.  According to the American Optometric Association, using phones, computers and other devices requires specific, but particularly demanding, &#8220;skills.&#8221;  Coordinating movement of our eyes, including eye movements, from one position to another;  accommodation, the ability to switch focus from one distance to another;  and vergence, focusing the eyes toward the nose and away from the nose depending on distance. &#8220;Our eyes are not designed to use computers and digital devices, especially for long periods of time,&#8221; says Dr. Robert C.  &#8220;As a result, many people who read or work on screens for long periods of time experience eye discomfort and vision problems,&#8221; Layman, a past president of the AOA, said in an email.  With the world we live in and all the great things at our fingertips, cutting screen time entirely is probably not realistic (although it can be done).  So here&#8217;s what to know about what plasters on a screen can do to your eyes and how to remove them safely.  Eye Strain and Blue Light: What Too Much &#8216;Screening&#8217; Does to Your Eyes  There has been a lot of debate about blue light  , which we get in large amounts from the sun and in small amounts from our screens.  Exposure to blue light signals to our body that it&#8217;s time to feel awake, which is one reason why using your phone before bed can be one of the biggest sleep disruptors, as it messes with our sleep-wake cycle.  While research shows that exposure to blue light from the sun over time can increase the risk of diseases that cause vision loss, including macular degeneration and cataracts, light from our electronics has yet to be shown to carry this risk.  devices according to the American Macular Degeneration Foundation.  Compared to the typical 1 microwatt of light coming through our screens, AMDF says, available research shows 3 microwatts or more of retinal cell damage.  Dr. Matt Starr, a clinical spokesman for the American Academy of Ophthalmology, said in an email that blue light by itself &#8220;does not cause permanent eye damage.&#8221;  Lehmann, however, said that overexposure to blue light can cause digital eye strain, which can lead to age-related vision problems in some patients.  Blue light effects aside, eye strain is a common and uncomfortable problem.  Although it can be experienced &#8220;somewhat differently from person to person,&#8221; according to Starr, it&#8217;s a group of symptoms that come from staring at a screen for long periods of time.  &#8220;Common symptoms include blurred vision, out-of-body sensation, itching, headache and dry eyes,&#8221; he said.  Interestingly, Layman says that screen time can lead to a higher risk of infection in some cases, because we blink less when looking at a screen.  &#8220;Blinking helps create and spread tears across the cornea, which keeps your eye hydrated,&#8221; Layman said.  &#8220;When the eyes don&#8217;t have enough tears to wash away the foreign material, they become prone to infection.&#8221;  We need more research on the effects of blue light from electronic screens.  But looking at your phone every night before bed is bad for your health anyway, because it disrupts your wake-wake cycle.  Cavan Images/Getty Images So do blue light glasses really work?  There really is still a proven medical benefit.  But there&#8217;s no harm in seeing if they help you.&#8221; Although some patients report the benefits of using blue light glasses while using computers, smartphones, and tablets to prevent eye strain, the reality is, there&#8217;s not enough science to support or disprove them. No. Benefit at this point,&#8221; Lehman said.  Personally, I occasionally use a pair of blue light glasses when I feel extra eye strain or I find myself needing extra focus, and I generally find it a bit easier to focus on my computer screen.  But I have no idea if it&#8217;s actually helping my eyes feel less strained, or if it&#8217;s just a placebo effect that helps me slightly change my perspective.  Starr confirms it&#8217;s likely the latter by pointing to this study from the American Journal of Ophthalmology, which found no difference between people wearing placebo glasses and blue light glasses.  But since blue light glasses are so cheap (I bought mine for under $15 online a few years ago) if you spend hours in front of a computer, they&#8217;re worth a test run to see if they help you at all.  Prices start around $9 at places like Walmart or Amazon, or you can read our review of the best blue light glasses.  Is using &#8216;dark mode&#8217; good for your eyes?  The biggest cheer from the audience at this year&#8217;s Google I/O event came when the tech company announced Bird, Google&#8217;s AI chatbot, was getting a dark mode.  But is it really something to celebrate, in terms of eye health?  This may depend on the brightness of the screen in the room you&#8217;re using it, according to Layman.  He said that &#8220;dark mode&#8221; can be good in a dimly lit, but not completely dark, room, and that light mode (black text on a white page, aka &#8220;positive polarity&#8221;) is better in a room with normal lighting.  Layman points to this study from 2013, which shows that positive polarity allows people to see details better.  Starr adds that using a dark mode, or turning on &#8220;night mode&#8221; on your phone, has some benefits in how easily our eyes are able to adjust.  &#8220;The contrast and colors used in night mode reduce glare and help our eyes adjust more easily to the surrounding light, resulting in less eye strain and easier, more comfortable reading,&#8221; he said.  As with blue light glasses, you should try playing with dark mode to see if it helps your eyes at all or makes them feel less strained.  Can Screen Time Make Bad Vision Worse?  When I went to the ophthalmologist last month for an eye exam, I asked my doctor this question and he said the research isn&#8217;t there to give a one-way causal answer.  There can be a chicken-or-egg scenario at play.  For example, people who are nearsighted may sit closer to their screens and potentially expose themselves to more eye strain or blue light, but this may not actively cause a poor prescription, but rather based on the fact that they can&#8217;t see well.  Have their faces scooch close to the screen.  Starr had a similar explanation: &#8220;There is some research that suggests close work activities, such as reading or using a screen for hours at a time, can lead to increased nearsightedness, especially in children whose eyes are still growing,&#8221; he said.  .According to the AAO&#8217;s data on vision development, studies have shown that children who spend an extra 40 minutes outside per day have a lower risk of developing myopia or severe myopia (very strong prescription), compared to children who spend more time indoors.  , either using computer devices or reading.  The AAO adds that there&#8217;s no direct link, but kids spending more time outdoors (and less screen time) are better for their health.  Also Read: Is Your Vision Worsening?  It&#8217;s time for eye exam tips to protect your eyes from technology Whether staring at a screen all day can permanently damage your eyesight, there are some simple steps you can take to make them feel more comfortable.  Keep your phone &#8220;reading distance&#8221; from your face.  This tip comes from the layman, who says it will reduce the focussing demands on your eyes  Make your font bigger  Another tip from the layman, upgrading your font size can make for a more comfortable viewing experience.  Follow the 20/20/20 rule.  Starr and Layman recommend that every 20 minutes, you take a 20-second break from your screen by looking 20 feet away.  &#8220;Blink, close your eyes, and look 20 feet away during the pause,&#8221; says Starr.  When possible, use a pen and paper.  (Even if you think it&#8217;s ridiculous.) This tip isn&#8217;t backed by science, but it&#8217;s helpful for me (I&#8217;m very nearsighted and work in front of a computer all day).  I use a physical notebook for a calendar because it&#8217;s a little relief for my eyes, which are usually glued to my laptop.  I use pen and paper to write something for fun and to take notes.  Limit screens to an hour or two before bed (and whenever you can).  This sleeping regimen is a tip from Starr.  Not only will limiting screen time before bed help your eyes, it can also help you feel less stressed and disengage from the day&#8217;s responsibilities.  Learn more about how to reduce phone time.  Both General and Starr emphasize the importance of eye exams, usually recommended at least every two years, but more often if you wear glasses or contacts, or if you experience discomfort or pain in the eye area.  Your eye doctor or ophthalmologist will be able to prescribe medicated drops or look for other causes of eye discomfort besides screen time, if you need it.  Also read: Turn off Instagram from your phone and thank me later</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnet.com/health/personal-care/all-that-screen-time-matters-when-it-comes-to-eye-health/#ftag=CAD590a51e">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.isis.poly.edu/all-screen-time-matters-for-eye-health-cnet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>TikTok is testing an AI chatbot for content discovery</title>
		<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu/tiktok-is-testing-an-ai-chatbot-for-content-discovery/</link>
					<comments>http://www.isis.poly.edu/tiktok-is-testing-an-ai-chatbot-for-content-discovery/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 18:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.isis.poly.edu/?p=13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TikTok may soon get a new way for users to discover content. The company is in the &#8220;early stages&#8221; of testing an AI-powered chatbot called Taco, which will be able to recommend videos and answer questions about what users are watching. The bot, which was first reported by TechCrunch, is currently being tested in the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TikTok may soon get a new way for users to discover content.  The company is in the &#8220;early stages&#8221; of testing an AI-powered chatbot called Taco, which will be able to recommend videos and answer questions about what users are watching.  The bot, which was first reported by TechCrunch, is currently being tested in the Philippines, TikTok said in a statement.  &#8220;Tako is powered by a third-party chat assistant and designed to help make it easier to discover entertaining and inspiring content on TikTok,&#8221; the company said.  Despite being in the early stages of testing, TikTok is apparently featuring tacos fairly prominently in the app.  A shortcut for Assistant sits in the right-hand menu alongside a shortcut to bookmarks, according to TechCrunch, which took a peek at the feature.  This is similar to the prominence Snap has given to its chatbot My AI in its app, pushing it to the top of user chats.  But unlike My AI, TikTok seems to be positioning Tako as a way to discover new content and learn more about what&#8217;s being discussed in clips.  Users should &#8220;feel free to ask me anything and I&#8217;ll do my best to help you find what you&#8217;re looking for,&#8221; the bot says in a screenshot of the chat interface.  Tako isn&#8217;t the only way TikTok is experimenting with generative AI.  The company is also testing AI-generated avatars, but has not announced plans for a wider rollout.  But it&#8217;s not clear for now how serious TikTok is about the technology.  In its statement, the company said Taco &#8220;has no current plans for this beyond these initial tests&#8221;.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/tiktok-is-testing-an-ai-chatbot-for-content-discovery-182119161.html?src=rss">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.isis.poly.edu/tiktok-is-testing-an-ai-chatbot-for-content-discovery/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
