<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; Instant News Portal</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:27:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>New research confirms: 20% of adults do not want children</title>
		<link>./../../../new-research-confirms-20-of-adults-do-not-want-children/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../new-research-confirms-20-of-adults-do-not-want-children/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/gitweb/?p=21</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The term &#8220;childfree&#8221; is used to describe individuals or couples who have made a conscious decision not to have children. This choice is often influenced by a variety of factors, including personal preference, lifestyle considerations, financial considerations, career aspirations, or concerns about overpopulation or environmental impact. Last summer, researchers at Michigan State University announced that]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The term &#8220;childfree&#8221; is used to describe individuals or couples who have made a conscious decision not to have children.  This choice is often influenced by a variety of factors, including personal preference, lifestyle considerations, financial considerations, career aspirations, or concerns about overpopulation or environmental impact.  Last summer, researchers at Michigan State University announced that about 1.7 million adults in Michigan, about one in five, have chosen not to have children, thus living a child-free life.  This figure was remarkably large, surprising many, and was later confirmed by a study  &#8220;We found that 20.9% of Michigan adults do not want children, which closely matches our previous estimate of 21.6%, and that means more than 1.6 million Michiganders are child-free,&#8221; said Jennifer Watling Neal, MSU professor of psychology and co-author of the study. .  &#8220;Michigan is similar to the U.S. as a whole in terms of population, so that could mean 50 million to 60 million Americans are child-free.&#8221;  The new study, published in PLOS ONE, attempted to replicate the original study using the same method, but with a new sample of humans.  The researchers used data from a representative sample of 1,000 adults who completed MSU&#8217;s State of the State survey, administered by the university&#8217;s Institute for Public Policy and Social Research.  To avoid any risk of cherry-picking results, the researchers pre-registered the study by recording in advance how the study would be conducted and what they hoped to find.  age, education or income,” said Zachary Neal, associate professor of psychology at MSU and co-author of the study.  &#8220;However, child-freedom is slightly more common among adults who are male, white or who have always been single.&#8221;  Some worry that child-free adults will regret their decision not to have children, especially later in life.  But Watling Neil explained &#8220;We found no evidence that older child-free adults experienced more life regrets than older parents. In fact, older parents were slightly more likely to want to change something about their lives.&#8221;  &#8220;Because many people are child-free, researchers say this group gets more attention, especially since reproductive rights are being eroded. Reproductive health care can force many people to have children even if they don&#8217;t want to, which is very concerning,&#8221; Neal said. The research team is now examining how abortion restrictions influence adults&#8217; choices to be childfree and is expanding their work beyond Michigan to include other states and countries. Reference: &#8220;Prevalence, Age of Decision, and Interpersonal Warmth Judgments of Childfree Adults: Replication and Extension&#8221; Jennifer Watling Neal and Zachary P. Neal, 5 Apr. 2023, PLOS ONE.DOI: 10.1317 /journal.pone.0283301<br />
<br /><a href="https://scitechdaily.com/new-study-confirms-20-of-adults-dont-want-children/">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../new-research-confirms-20-of-adults-do-not-want-children/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
