<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; DNews24</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.isis.poly.edu/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 12:57:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Chemical Maps: Mapping the Hidden World of Plant Roots</title>
		<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu/chemical-maps-mapping-the-hidden-world-of-plant-roots/</link>
					<comments>http://www.isis.poly.edu/chemical-maps-mapping-the-hidden-world-of-plant-roots/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 12:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.isis.poly.edu/?p=47</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UC San Diego and Stanford scientists studied maize (maize) plant roots and their metabolites—molecules involved in the plant&#8217;s energy production—under a variety of settings, including a control condition (left) and those treated with aconitate (middle) and succinate (right). Credit: Dickinson Lab, UC San Diego Researchers have used high-tech imaging originally developed for cancer research to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UC San Diego and Stanford scientists studied maize (maize) plant roots and their metabolites—molecules involved in the plant&#8217;s energy production—under a variety of settings, including a control condition (left) and those treated with aconitate (middle) and succinate (right).  Credit: Dickinson Lab, UC San Diego Researchers have used high-tech imaging originally developed for cancer research to gain new insights into important chemicals at work in plant roots.  This groundbreaking research has led to the development of a chemical &#8220;roadmap&#8221; that has significant implications for agricultural productivity, food creation and climate resilience.  When strolling through the park on a sunny spring day, it&#8217;s easy to overlook the unseen complexities beneath.  Terrestrial plant biologists, however, understand that the extensive, finely structured root systems that exist underground are fundamental to plant life and growth.  For example, a tree&#8217;s complex root networks may extend underground just as the tree itself reaches toward the sky  The research team, led by UC San Diego Biological Sciences Postdoctoral Scholar Tao Zhang and Assistant Professor Alexandra Dickinson, used an advanced imaging technique.  Search for corn plant roots.  They developed a &#8220;chemical roadmap&#8221; that details the distribution of important small molecules along plant stem cells and their effects on plant development.  Insights from this study, published in the journal Nature Communications, may provide key insights into how these essential key chemicals affect plant growth.  &#8220;This chemical roadmap provides a resource that scientists can use to find new ways to regulate plant growth,&#8221; said Dickinson, a faculty member in the Department of Cell and Developmental Biology.  &#8220;Having more information about how roots grow can be useful in conservation as we think about protecting our plants in natural environments and making them more sustainable, especially in agriculture.&#8221;  Researchers have used an advanced imaging technology to develop a new understanding of essential key chemicals that are responsible for plant growth.  Credit: Dickinson Lab, UC San Diego While working as a visiting scientist at Stanford University, Dickinson began collaborating with study co-first author Sarah Knoll and Professor Richard Zar, who developed a mass spectrometry imaging system that allows surgeons to distinguish between cancerous and benign tissue. helps to differentiate.  Tumor-removal operation.  Dickinson, Jarre and Knoll adapted the technique—called &#8220;desorption electrospray ionization mass spectrometry imaging&#8221; or DESI-MSI—to search plant roots for chemicals involved in growth and energy production.  They initially focused on corn plants at the root tip, where stem cells play an active role in plant development.  Their method involves cutting the center of the root to get a clear picture of the chemicals.  &#8220;To help understand plant roots biologically, we need to find out what chemicals are there,&#8221; Jarre said.  “Our imaging system sprays droplets that hit different parts of the root and dissolves the chemical at that location.  A mass spectrometer collects the droplet splash and tells us what those dissolved chemicals are.  By systematically scanning the droplet target spot, we create a spatial map of key chemicals.”  The resulting images, believed to be some of the first to reveal the transition between stem cells and mature root tissue, show the fundamental role metabolic-molecules play in plant energy production.  Tricarboxylic acid (TCA) cycle metabolites have become the focus of research as they have been found to be a key player in the regulation of root development.  Coming into the study, the researchers expected a relatively uniform distribution of the chemicals  Instead, with their chemical roadmap in hand, they found that TCA metabolites clustered in patches throughout the root.  &#8220;I was surprised at how many chemicals were characterized in really distinct patterns,&#8221; says Dickinson  &#8220;We can see that the plant is doing this on purpose—it needs these molecules in certain areas to grow properly.&#8221;  The Dickinson lab shows that these TCA metabolites have predictable effects on development, not only in corn, but also in another plant species (Arabidopsis).  This is likely because TCA metabolites are highly conserved – they are produced in all plants as well as animals  Also emerging from the new images were previously unknown chemical compounds  Dickinson says the mystery compounds may be important for plant growth because they also cluster in patterns at specific locations, suggesting a prominent role in development.  Dickinson and his colleagues are now investigating these compounds and comparing maize varieties with different levels of stress resistance to extreme climate conditions and adverse threats such as drought.  The new information will help them develop novel chemical and genetic strategies to improve plant growth and stress resilience.  “We&#8217;re looking at different drought-resistant corn plants to see if we&#8217;ve already found chemicals specific to that variety.  Not seen in other breeds,” said Dickinson.  &#8220;We think this could be a way to find new compounds that can promote growth, especially under harsh conditions.&#8221;  Reference: &#8220;Chemical Imaging Reveals Diverse Functions of Tricarboxylic Acid Metabolism in Root Growth and Development&#8221; Tao Zhang, Sarah E.  Knoll, by Jesus T.  Peng, Amman Claire, Abigail Tripka, Nathan Stutzman, Casey Cheng, Richard N.  Jarre, and Alexandra J.  Dickinson, 4 May 2023, Nature Communications.  DOI: 10.1038/s41467-023-38150 Research was funded by the National Science Foundation, National Institutes of Health, Hellman Foundation, William E.  McElroy Charitable Foundation, Ravel Provost Summer Research Scholarship, and the Genentech Scholars Program.<br />
<br /><a href="https://scitechdaily.com/chemical-cartography-mapping-the-hidden-world-of-plant-roots/">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.isis.poly.edu/chemical-maps-mapping-the-hidden-world-of-plant-roots/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NVIDIA&#8217;s generative AI allows gamers to interact with NPCs</title>
		<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu/nvidias-generative-ai-allows-gamers-to-interact-with-npcs/</link>
					<comments>http://www.isis.poly.edu/nvidias-generative-ai-allows-gamers-to-interact-with-npcs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 12:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.isis.poly.edu/?p=44</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NVIDIA unveiled technology called Avatar Cloud Engine (ACE) that allows gamers to naturally talk to non-playable characters (NPCs) and get appropriate responses. The company revealed the technology during its Generative AI keynote at Computex 2023, showing a demo called Kairos with a playable character talking to an NPC named Jin in a dystopic-looking ramen shop.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NVIDIA unveiled technology called Avatar Cloud Engine (ACE) that allows gamers to naturally talk to non-playable characters (NPCs) and get appropriate responses.  The company revealed the technology during its Generative AI keynote at Computex 2023, showing a demo called Kairos with a playable character talking to an NPC named Jin in a dystopic-looking ramen shop.  The demo (below 32:9, the widest widescreen I&#8217;ve seen) shows the player carrying on a conversation with Jean.  &#8220;Hey Gene, how are you,&#8221; the person asks.  &#8220;Unfortunately, not so good,&#8221; Jean replied.  &#8220;How?&#8221;  &#8220;I&#8217;m worried about crime here. It&#8217;s been bad lately. My ramen shop got caught in the crossfire.&#8221;  Yes, the dialogue is a little wooden;  Looks like ChatGPT might have done a better job.  Still, the idea is that you can just talk into your headset and an NPC will answer in the right context, making for a more natural interaction than you&#8217;d normally get in such a situation.  NVIDIA created the demo in partnership with Convai to promote ACE, which can run both in the cloud and locally (on NVIDIA hardware, natch).  It uses NVIDIA NeMo to create, customize, and deploy large language models that can be customized with lore and character backstories, while using Guardrails to protect against inappropriate dialogue.  It also deploys a speech recognition and speech-to-text tool called Riva with NVIDIA&#8217;s Omniverse Audio2Face &#8220;to instantly create expressive facial animations of a game character to match any speech track.&#8221;  The demo was built in Unreal Engine 5 to show off NVIDIA&#8217;s ray-tracing and other GPU features.  The visuals are actually more compelling than the AI ​​dialogue, though it&#8217;s easy to see how the latter could be vastly improved.  NVIDIA hasn&#8217;t announced any games that will use the technology, but Stalker 2: Heart of Chernobyl and Fort Solis Omniverse will employ Audio2Face.  All products recommended by Engadget are selected by our editorial team, independent of our parent company.  Some of our stories include affiliate links.  If you make a purchase through one of these links, we may earn an affiliate commission.  All prices correct at time of publication.<br />
<br /><a href="https://www.engadget.com/nvidias-generative-ai-lets-gamers-converse-with-npcs-124552730.html?src=rss">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.isis.poly.edu/nvidias-generative-ai-allows-gamers-to-interact-with-npcs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best Wireless Bluetooth Boom Boxes for 2023: Portable Pool and Beach Speakers, Ranked     &#8211; CNET</title>
		<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu/best-wireless-bluetooth-boom-boxes-for-2023-portable-pool-and-beach-speakers-ranked-cnet/</link>
					<comments>http://www.isis.poly.edu/best-wireless-bluetooth-boom-boxes-for-2023-portable-pool-and-beach-speakers-ranked-cnet/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 01:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.isis.poly.edu/?p=41</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[$140 at Amazon Anker Soundcore Motion Boom Plus Best new Bluetooth boom box $155 at Amazon Tribit Stormbox Blast Powerful Bluetooth boom box for less than $200 $229 at Amazon Soundcore by Anker Rave Party 2 Best new Bluetooth party speaker $300 at Amazon JBL Partybox Encore Essential Beefy yet compact boom box with light]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p> $140 at Amazon     Anker Soundcore Motion Boom Plus Best new Bluetooth boom box   $155 at Amazon     Tribit Stormbox Blast Powerful Bluetooth boom box for less than $200   $229 at Amazon     Soundcore by Anker Rave Party 2 Best new Bluetooth party speaker   $300 at Amazon     JBL Partybox Encore Essential Beefy yet compact boom box with light show<br />
      Show more (6 items)<br />
     Bluetooth speakers don&#8217;t only vary in terms of sound but also in shape and size. If you&#8217;re looking for a speaker that&#8217;s truly travel friendly, you&#8217;re going to want one of the top mini Bluetooth speakers. But if you&#8217;re looking for something with big sound that packs some real punch, a larger Bluetooth boom box or party speaker is the way to go.The speakers on this list all have rechargeable batteries and are considered portable speakers, though you may get a workout lugging some of these around. They weigh a minimum of 4 pounds (1.8 kilograms), and some weigh a lot more than that. All feature a built-in strap or handle that makes them easier to lug around. And they all have excellent battery life if you keep the volume at moderate levels, but if you really crank things up, you&#8217;re looking at much-reduced battery life numbers. Most are ready to go for whatever event you have in mind. From camping trips to beach parties, they&#8217;re all fairly rugged. Most offer a good degree of water resistance and a few are fully waterproof and dustproof. I&#8217;ve personally listened to all of these (or, in the case of the Soundcore Trance Go, I&#8217;ve listened to its nearly identical sibling speaker).Read more: Best Bluetooth Wireless Speaker for 2023   David Carnoy/CNET     Anker&#8217;s original Soundcore Motion Boom speaker (see below) has been on this list for a while and is still a decent value at a little more than $100. But the new-for-2022 Motion Boom Plus is significantly improved, particularly in terms of sound quality. It&#8217;s easily one of the best new Bluetooth speakers of 2022. Weighing 5.29 pounds (almost a pound more than the Motion Boom), it uses Bluetooth 5.3 and is equipped with upgraded dual 3.5-inch woofers and newly added dual 1-inch tweeters, delivering up to 80 watts of audio output (60W for the woofers and 20W for the tweeters). Battery life is rated for 20 hours at moderate volume levels. It&#8217;s also IP67 waterproof and dustproof and floats if you happen to drop it in a body of water.I was impressed with the sound quality, which measures up well against a few more expensive &#8212; and some larger &#8212; speakers on this list. You can tweak the sound profile (with EQ settings) and upgrade the speaker&#8217;s firmware in Anker&#8217;s Soundcore companion app for iOS and Android. I tended to go with the bass boost engaged &#8212; there&#8217;s a button on the speaker to activate it &#8212; and found that the speaker delivers full sound with good clarity in the mids and highs and good bass definition. For its size, the speaker is able to put out a lot of sound and mostly manages to avoid distorting at higher volumes (I tended to keep the volume in the 50-75% range). If you&#8217;re sitting within a few feet of the speaker, there&#8217;s a bit of stereo separation. But if you really want to up the sound quality, you can wirelessly pair two Soundcore Motion Boom Plus speakers to create a real stereo pair. Be sure to apply the $20 instant coupon when purchasing with Amazon to get the $160 price.        You&#8217;re receiving price alerts for Anker Soundcore Motion Boom Plus    David Carnoy/CNET     Tribit is known for its affordable smaller Bluetooth speakers that deliver very good sound quality and features for the price. Its new Stormbox Blast speaker is its first Bluetooth boom box speaker, and it delivers mostly impressive sound for its size and also has a built-in light show and USB-out charging. Weighing in at 12 pounds (5.45 kg) with two 30-watt midwoofers and two 15W tweeters, it&#8217;s basically twice as heavy as Anker&#8217;s Motion Boom Plus (see above) and pumps out more volume and bass compared to that speaker, but lacks a bit of clarity. Also, the midrange &#8212; where vocals live &#8212; is a bit recessed at its XBass default setting (I preferred the Music EQ setting in the companion app, which is a bit more balanced). The speaker&#8217;s firmware is upgradeable, and you can pair two Stormbox Blasts to create a stereo pair, which would improve the sound considerably. Battery life is very good. It&#8217;s rated at up 30 hours at moderate volume levels. And the speaker has an IPX7 rating, which means it&#8217;s fully waterproof. Again, like the Soundcore by Anker Motion Boom Plus, the Tribit Stormbox Blast is a good value that measures up well from a sound standpoint against more expensive JBL boom box speakers that arguably offer superior styling. Apply the $20 instant coupon when purchasing with Amazon, to ensure you get the $180 price.        You&#8217;re receiving price alerts for Tribit Stormbox Blast    Screenshot by David Carnoy/CNET     The Soundcore by Anker Rave Party 2 can be stood up vertically or laid down horizontally and features a built-in light show and handle. Like other larger speakers that boast higher power ratings (in this case, 120 watts), this speaker needs to be charged with its own AC adapter rather than a USB-cable and has a USB-A out port on the back for charging your smartphone or any other devices that need some juice. Though it costs more than Tribit&#8217;s Stormbox Blast, the 11.7-pound Rave Party 2 is a more attractively designed speaker and arguably sounds slightly better. Its two 4-inch woofers and two 2-inch tweeters deliver aggressive, punchy sound with enough volume to fill larger rooms (the Tribit&#8217;s bass goes a little deeper, but I was pretty satisfied with this speaker&#8217;s low-end capabilities). For even bigger sound, you can wirelessly link multiple Rave Party 2 and other Soundcore speakers that support the company&#8217;s PartyCast 2.0 feature. While this speaker isn&#8217;t fully waterproof and can&#8217;t float like some speakers can, it&#8217;s splash-proof, with an IPX4 rating, and has a microphone input with discrete gain and reverb controls (no microphone is included). In the companion app for iOS and Android, you can customize the sound profile and light show. Battery life is rated at up to 16 hours, but that number will drop if you crank the volume.I did think the sound held together pretty well at higher volumes &#8212; it mostly avoided distorting &#8212; and the speaker is designed to play loudly outdoors. That said, indoors the speaker sounds best below 75 percent volume, unless you&#8217;re having a party, in which case all critical listening goes out the door.         You&#8217;re receiving price alerts for Soundcore by Anker Rave Party 2    David Carnoy/CNET     JBL&#8217;s third-generation Boombox 3 features some design changes from its predecessor&#8217;s, including a new swankier handle and a new three-way driver system that delivers clearer more detailed sound and similar impressive bass performance, creating bigger, richer sound overall. I could easily hear the difference when comparing this model to the Boombox 2. While the battery life rating remains the same (up to 24 hours at moderate volume levels), this Gen 3 model includes Bluetooth 5.3 instead of Bluetooth 5.1. Also, the speaker weighs about 1.7 pounds more (14.7 pounds or 6.7 kg) and just feels that much more substantial. Like the UE Hyperboom (see below), this has a USB-out port that allows you to charge external devices like your phone, and there&#8217;s also an analog audio input if you want to go wired and connect a device without using Bluetooth connectivity (the Hyperboom adds an optical digital input).For outdoor use, I like the design of the Boombox 3 better than UE Hyperboom. The portable Bluetooth speaker is easier to carry around and just looks more like an outdoor speaker. It&#8217;s also fully waterproof and dustproof with an IPX67 rating (the previous model was waterproof but didn&#8217;t have a dustproof rating).With the JBL Boombox 2, I felt that the speaker, while well-designed, didn&#8217;t quite live up to its expensive price tag from a sound quality standpoint. The Boombox 3 is still pricey, but its sound now has a more premium quality to it &#8212; for portable boomboxes anyway. And if you have really deep pockets, you can link two together to create a stereo pair (or link several together to cover a wider area with sound).         You&#8217;re receiving price alerts for JBL Boombox 3    David Carnoy/CNET     The JBL Partybox Encore Essential is the company&#8217;s smallest PartyBox speaker to date but it&#8217;s still got some heft to it, weighing in at 13 pounds (5.9 kg). It&#8217;s a 11.54 by 10.87 by 12.87-inch cube that has a ring of light over the driver that pulsates and syncs to the beat of your music as it changes colors. The Essential is IPX4 splash-proof and has an integrated handle for easy toting. Rated for 100 watts of power (we always take power ratings with a grain of salt), the speaker doesn&#8217;t have quite the volume or sound quality of the step-up PartyBox 110 (see below). But it has a 5.25-inch woofer and two 1.75-inch tweeters and has plenty of kick to it, and it&#8217;s easier to carry around. In that sense, it offers a nice balance between size and power. Battery life is rated at 6 hours at moderate volume levels, and this speaker charges with an included AC adapter. It also has a charge-out port on the back along with a microphone port if you want to talk or sing to a crowd (microphone not included). To be clear, this is a mono speaker that&#8217;s designed to put out a lot of sound (there&#8217;s a bass boost mode) from a reasonably sized design. You can wirelessly pair two of these speakers and get significantly better sound (in stereo). But that would get a little pricey.        David Carnoy/CNET     Released in 2021, the PartyBox 110 packs some serious punch and delivers bigger sound than some of the portable boombox speakers on this list, including JBL&#8217;s own Boombox 2 (see below). There&#8217;s an integrated handle for toting the speaker, but the PartyBox 110 is pretty hefty, weighing in at 23 pounds and measuring slightly more than 22 inches tall. You can put this bluetooth boom box up vertically as shown in the picture above or place it horizontally, as it has rubber feet on both sides of the speaker.It&#8217;s rated for up to 12 hours of playback time at moderate volume levels and has a redesigned light show that syncs to the beat of your music (you can customize the light show from the speaker itself or use the JBL PartyBox companion app). The speaker has Bluetooth or a wired USB connection and there are guitar and mic inputs. It&#8217;s also worth noting that the speaker is IPX4 splash-proof and you can wirelessly link two PartyBox 110 speakers together for stereo sound. I didn&#8217;t test the stereo mode, but I was impressed with the sound of a single PartyBox 110 &#8212; this bluetooth device puts out lots of well-defined bass with good overall clarity in the highs and mids &#8212; and I suspect that pairing two of these together would be pretty awesome. I also liked how the speaker has no external AC adapter brick and only requires a cord for charging (the power adapter is in the speaker). For longer parties during which you&#8217;re really cranking the tunes, you&#8217;d want to plug the speaker in if possible. But it does deliver enough volume to fill a spacious living room with sound and also plays loud enough for a small pool or beach party. The PartyBox 710 ($800) is a massive party speaker that has integrated wheels and requires a power source to operate; it does not have an integrated rechargeable battery. This is your best bet if you want a portable speaker that can deliver big, quality sound and operates on battery power. To be clear, this offers bigger and better sound than the JBL Boombox 2 &#8212; but it is harder to carry around.       David Carnoy/CNET     Anker&#8217;s Soundcore Motion Boom is what I&#8217;d call a mini portable boombox speaker. It&#8217;s kind of a poor man&#8217;s version of JBL&#8217;s well-regarded Xtreme 3 speaker, which lists for $350. Equipped with a handle and weighing a little over 4 pounds, the speaker reminds me of one of those giant flashlights or &#8220;floating lanterns&#8221; that were in vogue about 30 years ago. For the record, the Motion Boom actually does float and it&#8217;s got an IPX7   waterproof rating. Anker says the Motion Boom delivers &#8220;huge stereo sound&#8221; and, yes, this portable bluetooth speaker plays pretty loud and has a decent amount of bass with reasonable clarity &#8212; but I wouldn&#8217;t call it huge and there&#8217;s not much stereo separation (I kept the bass boost on at all times because the speaker sounds better that way.) It can&#8217;t compete against bigger and more expensive speakers like JBL&#8217;s Boombox 2 ($500) and Ultimate Ears&#8217; Hyperboom ($400), but it packs a lot more volume and punch than more compact Bluetooth speakers like JBL&#8217;s Flip 5 that cost around the same. It also travels well, so it&#8217;s ideal for a beach excursion or a little tailgating. It also can be used as a backup battery to charge your smartphone or other mobile device.The newer Motion Boom Plus (see above) does offer a significant bump in sound quality for about $65 to $75 more, depending on pricing fluctuations. If you can afford it, the Motion Boom Plus is the better option. If you want to go smaller, the Anker Soundcore Motion Plus Bluetooth speaker delivers very good sound for its size. It&#8217;s not a Bluetooth boombox, however, and doesn&#8217;t feature an integrated handle like the Motion Boom and Motion Boom Plus.        You&#8217;re receiving price alerts for Anker Soundcore Motion Boom    David Carnoy/CNET     Sony&#8217;s SRS-XG500 is the most direct competitor to the JBL Boombox 2. They&#8217;re similarly priced and sized, with both featuring an integrated handle. The Sony is a little larger but weighs slightly less at 12.34 pounds (5.6 kg). I went back and forth comparing the sound of the two speakers. While I liked the JBL&#8217;s sound a bit more because it came across as sounding a little clearer with better detail, the Sony pumps out a lot of bass &#8212; it has a warmer, boomier sound quality that some people may prefer.It&#8217;s IP66 water-resistant and dustproof, meaning it can take a sustained spray of water but it can&#8217;t be fully submerged. You also get a mic/guitar rear input and dual USB-out ports for charging your devices. (The speaker has its own power adapter; you can&#8217;t charge it via USB-C.) Battery life is rated at 30 hours at moderate volume levels, which is very good. Crank your tunes and that number drops substantially. At night, you can light up the speaker with the LED light strips that ring the inside of the bass ports and use the Fiestable app to control the LEDs. The Sony Music app allows you to tweak the sound profile. Additionally, you can link the speaker with other Sony Bluetooth speakers to augment the sound.         Watch this: JBL Boombox 2 vs. UE Hyperboom: Battle of the portable Bluetooth beasts<br />
          04:13     David Carnoy/CNET     The UE Hyperboom has a few things going for it over the Boombox 2. For starters, the price: It&#8217;s $450 while the Boombox 2 is $500. And right now you can get $22 off, when you apply the coupon on Amazon.For outdoor use, I give the nod to the JBL&#8217;s design. Both of these weigh 13 pounds, but the JBL is a little more natural to carry around. It&#8217;s got the handle, the tubular design &#8212; it looks like it belongs outdoors. The Hyperboom&#8217;s got a thick rubber strap and it kind of feels like you&#8217;re carrying a big pitcher of something really solid. It&#8217;s boxy and understated, and it looks a little more at home indoors.The Hyperboom is splashproof with an IPX4 rating while the Boombox 2 is fully waterproof with an IPX7 rating. (I put them out in the rain and they both survived without issues.) Like the Boombox 2, this has a USB-out port that allows you to charge devices like your phone and it also has analog audio input if you want to go wired and connect a device without using Bluetooth. However, the Hyperboom adds an optical digital input. That means you can connect it to a TV, PC or game console with an optical output. You can also toggle between two Bluetooth connections and it has a built-in microphone that calibrates the speaker&#8217;s sound to wherever it is, inside or outside.The Hyperboom also is the better-sounding portable Bluetooth speaker overall. It has a wider soundstage with slightly more bass and clarity. It also sounds a little more natural. If you can afford it, you can link up two Hyperbooms and create a stereo pair. You can also link it wirelessly to the latest UE Bluetooth speakers to spread out the sound across a wider area. Read our Ultimate Ears Hyperboom review.<br />
            Amazon     Last year I reviewed Anker&#8217;s Soundcore Rave Neo party speaker and gave it high marks. The Trance Go is essentially that speaker without the integrated LEDs that allow you to create a mini light show. It costs right around $100, plays loud for its size (it&#8217;s a medium-size speaker that weighs about 6 pounds) and has a built-in handle that makes it easy to tote around. The speaker is fully waterproof and can get up to 24 hours on a single charge at moderate levels. A USB port allows you to charge devices. Also worth noting: For those who want more expansive sound for streaming music, you can link multiple Trance Go speakers.        David Carnoy/CNET     If you don&#8217;t want to get something quite as big as the JBL Boombox 2, the Xtreme 3 weighs a good deal less but is still large by Bluetooth speaker standards and puts out a lot of sound (though not as much as the Boombox 2). Instead of a built-in handle, a detachable shoulder strap is included.Like JBL&#8217;s smaller Bluetooth speakers, the Xtreme 3 is a versatile boom box that can be stood up vertically or placed horizontally. Though a tad bigger than the Xtreme 2, at first glance it doesn&#8217;t look much different from the previous model, but it does have upgraded sound with slightly better bass and clarity while actually weighing slightly less. Here are the key differences between the two speakers, according to JBL: Plays slightly louder: The Xtreme 3&#8217;s rated output power is 2 x 25W versus the Xtreme 2&#8217;s 2 x 20W.The Xtreme 3 is IPX67 (waterproof/dustproof) versus the Xtreme 2&#8217;s IPX7 (waterproof).The Xtreme 3 offers JBL PartyBoost while the Xtreme 2 has JBL Connected Plus syncing technologies.The Xtreme 3 improves charge time to just 2.5 hours, down from 3.5 hours for the Xtreme 2 (both have 15 hours of battery life)The Xtreme 3 has Bluetooth 5.1, the Xtreme 2 has Bluetooth 4.2 .The Xtreme 3 is slightly larger but at 4.3 pounds weighs less than the Xtreme 2, which is 5.3 pounds.    More audio recommendations<br />
<br /><a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/home-entertainment/best-wireless-bluetooth-boombox/#ftag=CAD590a51e">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.isis.poly.edu/best-wireless-bluetooth-boom-boxes-for-2023-portable-pool-and-beach-speakers-ranked-cnet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to join a node in a docker swarm</title>
		<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu/how-to-join-a-node-in-a-docker-swarm/</link>
					<comments>http://www.isis.poly.edu/how-to-join-a-node-in-a-docker-swarm/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 17:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.isis.poly.edu/?p=37</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jack Wallen walks through the steps to join new nodes to a Docker swarm as a worker and manager to help manage larger Docker clusters. Do you have a docker swarm up and running and need to add more nodes to it? You probably remember how getting started with Docker Swarm introduced you to the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>
<p>    Jack Wallen walks through the steps to join new nodes to a Docker swarm as a worker and manager to help manage larger Docker clusters.  Do you have a docker swarm up and running and need to add more nodes to it?  You probably remember how getting started with Docker Swarm introduced you to the join command.  The join token from that command can only be used once, so even if you copy that command to a file, it won&#8217;t work for a new node.  Fortunately, however, Docker developers have made it possible to add new nodes to a swarm at any time.  To do this, you need to have a Docker swarm up and running with at least one controller node and a new node to join.  You can add as many nodes as you need and can do so at any time.  You can join a node as a worker or manager.  The difference is simple: manager nodes elect a leader to manage orchestration tasks, whereas worker nodes receive and execute tasks sent from manager nodes.  Presumably, you&#8217;ll join the node as a worker, but I&#8217;ll show you the commands for both.  First, let&#8217;s join a node as a worker.  Log in to your Docker Swarm controller node and issue the docker swarm join-token worker command.  The output will include the docker swarm join command that you run on the new worker node.  If you want to create a new token, use the rotate option like this: docker swarm join-token &#8211;rotate worker.  Now, if you want to join a node as a manager, the command is docker swarm join-token manager.  To create a new join token, you can use the rotate option in the same way as with the docker swarm join-token &#8211;rotate manager.  Once you run one of those commands on your new node, it will join the swarm as a worker or a manager, and you&#8217;re ready to develop and manage a larger Docker cluster.  Subscribe to TechRepublic&#8217;s How To Make Tech Work on YouTube for Jack Wallen&#8217;s latest technology advice for business professionals.<br />
<br /><a href="https://www.techrepublic.com/article/how-to-join-node-docker-swarm/">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.isis.poly.edu/how-to-join-a-node-in-a-docker-swarm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New research confirms: 20% of adults do not want children</title>
		<link>http://www.isis.poly.edu/new-research-confirms-20-of-adults-do-not-want-children/</link>
					<comments>http://www.isis.poly.edu/new-research-confirms-20-of-adults-do-not-want-children/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/gitweb/?p=21</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The term &#8220;childfree&#8221; is used to describe individuals or couples who have made a conscious decision not to have children. This choice is often influenced by a variety of factors, including personal preference, lifestyle considerations, financial considerations, career aspirations, or concerns about overpopulation or environmental impact. Last summer, researchers at Michigan State University announced that]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The term &#8220;childfree&#8221; is used to describe individuals or couples who have made a conscious decision not to have children.  This choice is often influenced by a variety of factors, including personal preference, lifestyle considerations, financial considerations, career aspirations, or concerns about overpopulation or environmental impact.  Last summer, researchers at Michigan State University announced that about 1.7 million adults in Michigan, about one in five, have chosen not to have children, thus living a child-free life.  This figure was remarkably large, surprising many, and was later confirmed by a study  &#8220;We found that 20.9% of Michigan adults do not want children, which closely matches our previous estimate of 21.6%, and that means more than 1.6 million Michiganders are child-free,&#8221; said Jennifer Watling Neal, MSU professor of psychology and co-author of the study. .  &#8220;Michigan is similar to the U.S. as a whole in terms of population, so that could mean 50 million to 60 million Americans are child-free.&#8221;  The new study, published in PLOS ONE, attempted to replicate the original study using the same method, but with a new sample of humans.  The researchers used data from a representative sample of 1,000 adults who completed MSU&#8217;s State of the State survey, administered by the university&#8217;s Institute for Public Policy and Social Research.  To avoid any risk of cherry-picking results, the researchers pre-registered the study by recording in advance how the study would be conducted and what they hoped to find.  age, education or income,” said Zachary Neal, associate professor of psychology at MSU and co-author of the study.  &#8220;However, child-freedom is slightly more common among adults who are male, white or who have always been single.&#8221;  Some worry that child-free adults will regret their decision not to have children, especially later in life.  But Watling Neil explained &#8220;We found no evidence that older child-free adults experienced more life regrets than older parents. In fact, older parents were slightly more likely to want to change something about their lives.&#8221;  &#8220;Because many people are child-free, researchers say this group gets more attention, especially since reproductive rights are being eroded. Reproductive health care can force many people to have children even if they don&#8217;t want to, which is very concerning,&#8221; Neal said. The research team is now examining how abortion restrictions influence adults&#8217; choices to be childfree and is expanding their work beyond Michigan to include other states and countries. Reference: &#8220;Prevalence, Age of Decision, and Interpersonal Warmth Judgments of Childfree Adults: Replication and Extension&#8221; Jennifer Watling Neal and Zachary P. Neal, 5 Apr. 2023, PLOS ONE.DOI: 10.1317 /journal.pone.0283301<br />
<br /><a href="https://scitechdaily.com/new-study-confirms-20-of-adults-dont-want-children/">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://www.isis.poly.edu/new-research-confirms-20-of-adults-do-not-want-children/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
