<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Health &#8211; Instant News Portal</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 02:36:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Brain implants allow paralyzed people to walk using their thoughts</title>
		<link>./../../../brain-implants-allow-paralyzed-people-to-walk-using-their-thoughts/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../brain-implants-allow-paralyzed-people-to-walk-using-their-thoughts/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 02:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/gitweb/?p=34</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gert-Jan Oskam was living in China in 2011 when he was in a motorcycle accident that left him paralyzed from the hips down. Now, with a combination of devices, scientists have given him back control over his lower body. &#8220;For 12 years I&#8217;ve been trying to get my legs back,&#8221; Mr Oskam said at a]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gert-Jan Oskam was living in China in 2011 when he was in a motorcycle accident that left him paralyzed from the hips down.  Now, with a combination of devices, scientists have given him back control over his lower body.  &#8220;For 12 years I&#8217;ve been trying to get my legs back,&#8221; Mr Oskam said at a press briefing on Tuesday.  &#8220;Now I&#8217;ve learned how to walk naturally, naturally.&#8221;  In a study published Wednesday in the journal Nature, researchers in Switzerland described implants that provided a &#8220;digital bridge&#8221; between Mr. Oskam&#8217;s brain and his spinal cord, bypassing the injured parts.  The invention allows Mr Oskam, 40, to stand, walk and climb a steep ramp with only the aid of a walker.  More than a year after the implant was inserted, he retained these abilities and actually showed signs of neurological recovery, walking with crutches even after the implant was removed.  Grégoire Courtaine, a spinal cord specialist at the Swiss Federal Institute of Technology, Lausanne, who led the study, said at a press briefing.  Neuroscientist Jocelyn Bloch.  &#8220;It was quite science fiction for me at the beginning, but today it has become reality,&#8221; added Mr Oskam, who implanted Mr Oskam at the University of Lausanne.  In recent years there have been several advances in technological spinal cord injury treatment.  In 2016, a group of scientists led by Dr. Courtin managed to restore the ability to walk in paralyzed monkeys and helped another man regain control of his paralyzed arm.  In 2018, a different team of scientists, led by Dr Courtin, developed a way to stimulate the brain with electrical-pulse generators, allowing partially paralyzed people to walk and cycle again.  Last year, more advanced brain stimulation methods allowed paralyzed people to swim, walk and cycle within a day of treatment.  Mr.  Oskam underwent stimulation procedures in earlier years, and even regained the ability to walk, but eventually his progress plateaued.  At the press briefing, Mr. Oskam said that these stimulation technologies made him feel that there was something alien about locomotion, an alien distance between his mind and body.  The new interface changed that, he said: “Earlier the stimulus was controlling.  I am, and now I am controlling the impulse.”  In the new study, the brain-spinal interface, as the researchers call it, took advantage of an artificial intelligence thought decoder to read Mr. Oskam&#8217;s intentions — detectable as his electrical signals.  brain &#8211; and their muscle movements to match.  The etiology of natural movement, from thought to intention, was preserved.  The only addition, as Dr.  Courtaine describes the digital bridge spanning the injured parts of the spine.  Andrew Jackson, a neuroscientist at Newcastle University who was not involved in the research, said: &#8220;It raises interesting questions about autonomy, and the source of order. You keep blurring the philosophical boundaries between what the brain is and what technology is.&#8221;  Dr. Jackson added that scientists in the field have theorized about connecting the brain to spinal cord stimuli for decades, but this represents the first time they&#8217;ve achieved such success in a human patient. &#8220;It&#8217;s easy to say, it&#8217;s much harder to do.&#8221; ,&#8221; he said. To achieve these results, the researchers first implanted electrodes on Mr. Oskam&#8217;s skull and spine. The team then used a machine-learning program to observe which parts of the brain lit up as he tried to move different parts of his body. This thought decoder is specific. were able to match the activity of specific electrodes to the target: one configuration lit up whenever Mr. Oskam tried to move his ankle, another when he tried to move his hip. The researchers then used another algorithm to connect the brain implant to the spinal implant, which was in his body. Different parts were set to send electrical signals, sparking movement. The algorithm was able to account for slight changes in the direction and speed of each muscle contraction and relaxation.  And, because the signals between the brain and spinal cord were sent every 300 milliseconds, Mr. Oskam could quickly adjust his technique based on what was working and what wasn&#8217;t.  He can twist his hip muscles within the first treatment session  Over the next few months, researchers fine-tuned the brain-spinal interface to better accommodate basic actions like walking and standing.  Mr. Oskam regained a somewhat healthy range of motion and was able to navigate steps and ramps with relative ease without treatment for several months.  Furthermore, after a year of treatment, he began to notice a clear improvement in his movement without the aid of a brain-spinal interface.  Researchers documented these improvements in weight bearing, balance and walking tests  Now, Mr Oskam can walk limited distances around his home, get in and out of cars and stop at a bar for a drink.  For the first time, she said, she felt like she was in control  The researchers acknowledge the limitations of their work  It is difficult to distinguish subtle motives in the brain, and although the current brain-spine interface is suitable for walking, the same probably cannot be said for restoring upper body movement.  Treatment is also invasive, requiring multiple surgeries and hours of physical therapy.  The current system does not correct all spinal cord paralysis  But the team is hopeful that further advances will make the treatment more accessible and more systemically effective  &#8220;That&#8217;s our real objective,&#8221; said Dr. Courtaine, &#8220;to make this technology available around the world to all patients who need it.&#8221;<br />
<br /><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/05/24/science/paralysis-brain-implants-ai.html">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../brain-implants-allow-paralyzed-people-to-walk-using-their-thoughts/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>All screen time matters for eye health &#8211; CNET</title>
		<link>./../../../all-screen-time-matters-for-eye-health-cnet/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../all-screen-time-matters-for-eye-health-cnet/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 18:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost/gitweb/?p=15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anyone who&#8217;s lost track of three hours staring at their computer may be familiar with the feeling of eyeballs plastered to the screen. As it turns out, staring at our phones, tablets and laptops for many hours a day is not good for our eyes. This can cause symptoms of digital eye strain, which stems]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anyone who&#8217;s lost track of three hours staring at their computer may be familiar with the feeling of eyeballs plastered to the screen.  As it turns out, staring at our phones, tablets and laptops for many hours a day is not good for our eyes.  This can cause symptoms of digital eye strain, which stems from the hard work our eyes have to do when navigating a screen.  According to the American Optometric Association, using phones, computers and other devices requires specific, but particularly demanding, &#8220;skills.&#8221;  Coordinating movement of our eyes, including eye movements, from one position to another;  accommodation, the ability to switch focus from one distance to another;  and vergence, focusing the eyes toward the nose and away from the nose depending on distance. &#8220;Our eyes are not designed to use computers and digital devices, especially for long periods of time,&#8221; says Dr. Robert C.  &#8220;As a result, many people who read or work on screens for long periods of time experience eye discomfort and vision problems,&#8221; Layman, a past president of the AOA, said in an email.  With the world we live in and all the great things at our fingertips, cutting screen time entirely is probably not realistic (although it can be done).  So here&#8217;s what to know about what plasters on a screen can do to your eyes and how to remove them safely.  Eye Strain and Blue Light: What Too Much &#8216;Screening&#8217; Does to Your Eyes  There has been a lot of debate about blue light  , which we get in large amounts from the sun and in small amounts from our screens.  Exposure to blue light signals to our body that it&#8217;s time to feel awake, which is one reason why using your phone before bed can be one of the biggest sleep disruptors, as it messes with our sleep-wake cycle.  While research shows that exposure to blue light from the sun over time can increase the risk of diseases that cause vision loss, including macular degeneration and cataracts, light from our electronics has yet to be shown to carry this risk.  devices according to the American Macular Degeneration Foundation.  Compared to the typical 1 microwatt of light coming through our screens, AMDF says, available research shows 3 microwatts or more of retinal cell damage.  Dr. Matt Starr, a clinical spokesman for the American Academy of Ophthalmology, said in an email that blue light by itself &#8220;does not cause permanent eye damage.&#8221;  Lehmann, however, said that overexposure to blue light can cause digital eye strain, which can lead to age-related vision problems in some patients.  Blue light effects aside, eye strain is a common and uncomfortable problem.  Although it can be experienced &#8220;somewhat differently from person to person,&#8221; according to Starr, it&#8217;s a group of symptoms that come from staring at a screen for long periods of time.  &#8220;Common symptoms include blurred vision, out-of-body sensation, itching, headache and dry eyes,&#8221; he said.  Interestingly, Layman says that screen time can lead to a higher risk of infection in some cases, because we blink less when looking at a screen.  &#8220;Blinking helps create and spread tears across the cornea, which keeps your eye hydrated,&#8221; Layman said.  &#8220;When the eyes don&#8217;t have enough tears to wash away the foreign material, they become prone to infection.&#8221;  We need more research on the effects of blue light from electronic screens.  But looking at your phone every night before bed is bad for your health anyway, because it disrupts your wake-wake cycle.  Cavan Images/Getty Images So do blue light glasses really work?  There really is still a proven medical benefit.  But there&#8217;s no harm in seeing if they help you.&#8221; Although some patients report the benefits of using blue light glasses while using computers, smartphones, and tablets to prevent eye strain, the reality is, there&#8217;s not enough science to support or disprove them. No. Benefit at this point,&#8221; Lehman said.  Personally, I occasionally use a pair of blue light glasses when I feel extra eye strain or I find myself needing extra focus, and I generally find it a bit easier to focus on my computer screen.  But I have no idea if it&#8217;s actually helping my eyes feel less strained, or if it&#8217;s just a placebo effect that helps me slightly change my perspective.  Starr confirms it&#8217;s likely the latter by pointing to this study from the American Journal of Ophthalmology, which found no difference between people wearing placebo glasses and blue light glasses.  But since blue light glasses are so cheap (I bought mine for under $15 online a few years ago) if you spend hours in front of a computer, they&#8217;re worth a test run to see if they help you at all.  Prices start around $9 at places like Walmart or Amazon, or you can read our review of the best blue light glasses.  Is using &#8216;dark mode&#8217; good for your eyes?  The biggest cheer from the audience at this year&#8217;s Google I/O event came when the tech company announced Bird, Google&#8217;s AI chatbot, was getting a dark mode.  But is it really something to celebrate, in terms of eye health?  This may depend on the brightness of the screen in the room you&#8217;re using it, according to Layman.  He said that &#8220;dark mode&#8221; can be good in a dimly lit, but not completely dark, room, and that light mode (black text on a white page, aka &#8220;positive polarity&#8221;) is better in a room with normal lighting.  Layman points to this study from 2013, which shows that positive polarity allows people to see details better.  Starr adds that using a dark mode, or turning on &#8220;night mode&#8221; on your phone, has some benefits in how easily our eyes are able to adjust.  &#8220;The contrast and colors used in night mode reduce glare and help our eyes adjust more easily to the surrounding light, resulting in less eye strain and easier, more comfortable reading,&#8221; he said.  As with blue light glasses, you should try playing with dark mode to see if it helps your eyes at all or makes them feel less strained.  Can Screen Time Make Bad Vision Worse?  When I went to the ophthalmologist last month for an eye exam, I asked my doctor this question and he said the research isn&#8217;t there to give a one-way causal answer.  There can be a chicken-or-egg scenario at play.  For example, people who are nearsighted may sit closer to their screens and potentially expose themselves to more eye strain or blue light, but this may not actively cause a poor prescription, but rather based on the fact that they can&#8217;t see well.  Have their faces scooch close to the screen.  Starr had a similar explanation: &#8220;There is some research that suggests close work activities, such as reading or using a screen for hours at a time, can lead to increased nearsightedness, especially in children whose eyes are still growing,&#8221; he said.  .According to the AAO&#8217;s data on vision development, studies have shown that children who spend an extra 40 minutes outside per day have a lower risk of developing myopia or severe myopia (very strong prescription), compared to children who spend more time indoors.  , either using computer devices or reading.  The AAO adds that there&#8217;s no direct link, but kids spending more time outdoors (and less screen time) are better for their health.  Also Read: Is Your Vision Worsening?  It&#8217;s time for eye exam tips to protect your eyes from technology Whether staring at a screen all day can permanently damage your eyesight, there are some simple steps you can take to make them feel more comfortable.  Keep your phone &#8220;reading distance&#8221; from your face.  This tip comes from the layman, who says it will reduce the focussing demands on your eyes  Make your font bigger  Another tip from the layman, upgrading your font size can make for a more comfortable viewing experience.  Follow the 20/20/20 rule.  Starr and Layman recommend that every 20 minutes, you take a 20-second break from your screen by looking 20 feet away.  &#8220;Blink, close your eyes, and look 20 feet away during the pause,&#8221; says Starr.  When possible, use a pen and paper.  (Even if you think it&#8217;s ridiculous.) This tip isn&#8217;t backed by science, but it&#8217;s helpful for me (I&#8217;m very nearsighted and work in front of a computer all day).  I use a physical notebook for a calendar because it&#8217;s a little relief for my eyes, which are usually glued to my laptop.  I use pen and paper to write something for fun and to take notes.  Limit screens to an hour or two before bed (and whenever you can).  This sleeping regimen is a tip from Starr.  Not only will limiting screen time before bed help your eyes, it can also help you feel less stressed and disengage from the day&#8217;s responsibilities.  Learn more about how to reduce phone time.  Both General and Starr emphasize the importance of eye exams, usually recommended at least every two years, but more often if you wear glasses or contacts, or if you experience discomfort or pain in the eye area.  Your eye doctor or ophthalmologist will be able to prescribe medicated drops or look for other causes of eye discomfort besides screen time, if you need it.  Also read: Turn off Instagram from your phone and thank me later</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnet.com/health/personal-care/all-that-screen-time-matters-when-it-comes-to-eye-health/#ftag=CAD590a51e">Source link </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../all-screen-time-matters-for-eye-health-cnet/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
